protective.com 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy | Protective Life

### Effective June 28, 2017

Protective Life recognizes that protecting the privacy and security of personal information is an important responsibility. This Online Privacy Policy tells you how we treat personal information that we collect when you use the website from which you are accessing this Online Privacy Policy and the measures we take to safeguard that information. 

This notice refers to Protective Life and its affiliated companies using the terms “we,” “us,” and “our.” 

### Using Our Websites and Sharing Personal Information with Us 

You can access extensive information about our products on our websites and social media sites without sharing any personal information with us. 

We may also provide online tools and resources that allow you to share personal information with us. Those tools and resources are designed to use personal information so that we can give you a personalized response to an inquiry, or provide you with information about services and products that may meet your needs.

When you share personal information with us for these purposes, we may share that information with our affiliates, or with other companies who help us respond to your questions or market our own products to you. We will not share personal information with anyone else unless we have your permission, or we are allowed or required by law to disclose it. 

### How We Safeguard Personal Information 

We seek to maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect personal information within our organization.

### Important Information for Protective Life Customers 

If you are a Protective Life client or policyholder, our Customer Privacy Policy applies to any personal information that you share with us online. Please click [here to read our Customer Privacy Policy.](https://www.protective.com/privacy-policy/customer-privacy-policy/ "here to read our Customer Privacy Policy")

If you are a Zurich American life Insurance Company Customer whose policy is administered by Protective Life, please click [here](https://www.protective.com/privacy-policy/zal/) to read the privacy notice that applies to your policy.

### Other Information We Receive from Visitors to Our Websites 

We may collect other information—which is information that does not reveal your specific identity or relate to an identifiable individual—in a variety of ways, including:

  * **Through your browser or device:** Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, and Internet browser type and version. We use this information to ensure that our websites function properly. 

  * **Using cookies:** Cookies are pieces of information stored directly on the computer that you are using. Cookies allow us to collect information such as browser type, time spent on our websites, pages visited, language preferences, and other traffic data. We use the information for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, to personalize your experience while using the websites, and to recognize your computer in order to assist your use of the websites. 

We also gather statistical information about use of the websites in order to continually improve their design and functionality, understand how they are used and assist us with resolving questions regarding them. We may also use cookies or other technologies to track responses to our online advertisements.

If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to automatically decline cookies or be given the choice of declining or accepting the transfer to your computer of a particular cookie (or cookies) from a particular site. You may also wish to refer to <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/>. If, however, you do not accept cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of our websites. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer, and you may need to log in every time you visit. 

  * **Using pixel tags and other similar technologies:** Pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) may be used in connection with our websites to, among other things, track the actions of users (including email recipients), measure the success of our marketing campaigns, and compile statistics about use of the websites and response rates. 

We do not respond to browser do-not-track signals at this time. 

  * **Analytics**. We use certain analytics services, which use cookies and similar technologies to collect and analyze information about use of the websites and report on activities and trends. 

You can learn about our service provider Google’s analytics practices by going to [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/), and opt out of them by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. 

You can learn about our service provider Optimizely’s analytics practices, and how to opt out of them, at <https://www.optimizely.com/opt_out/>. 

This site uses the Lucky Orange analytics system to help improve usability and the customer experience. Lucky Orange may record mouse clicks, mouse movements and scrolling activity. Lucky Orange may record keystroke information that you voluntarily enter on this website. Lucky Orange does not track this activity on any site that does not use the Lucky Orange system. You can choose to disable the Lucky Orange Service at <http://www.luckyorange.com/disable.php>. Note, that doing so will disable other features of the Lucky Orange system that this site employs such as 1-to-1 support chat. 

  * **Using Adobe Flash technology:** We may use Adobe Flash Local Shared Objects (“Flash LSOs”) to, among other things, collect and store information about your use of the websites. You can control Flash LSOs by going to the [Global Storage Settings Panel](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager03.html) on the Macromedia site. 

  * **IP Address:** Your IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider. An IP address may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user accesses our website, along with the time of the visit and the pages visited. Collecting IP addresses is standard practice and is done automatically by many websites, applications, and other services. We use IP addresses for purposes such as calculating use levels, diagnosing server problems, and administering the websites. We may also derive your approximate location from your IP address.

We may use and disclose the other information described above for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. If we combine such information with personal information, we will treat the combined information as personal information.

### Our Advertising 

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements regarding products and services that may be of interest to you when you access and use our websites and applications, and other websites and online services, based on information relating to your access to and use of any such services on any of your devices, as well as on information received from third parties. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through the use of pixel tags).

They may also use these technologies, along with information they collect about your online use, to recognize you across the devices you use, such as a mobile phone and a laptop. If you would like more information about this practice, and to learn how to opt out of it in desktop and mobile browsers on the particular device on which you are accessing this Online Privacy Policy, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> and <http://www.aboutads.info/>. 

Our online advertising practices are designed to comply with the Digital Advertising Alliance Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising.

### Keeping Up To Date with our Online Privacy Policy 

We have the right to change our Online Privacy Policy. If we make a material change to this policy, we will post a notification on our website before we put the change into effect.
